import { QuizSet } from "../_types";

export const commonVerbs2: QuizSet = {
  id: 2,
  name: "Common Verbs - 2",
  questions: [
    {
      id: 26,
      question: "How do you say 'call' in Polish?",
      options: ["telefonować", "wołać", "dzwonić", "nazywać"],
      correctAnswer: 2,
    },
    {
      id: 27,
      question: "How do you say 'try' in Polish?",
      options: ["usiłować", "testować", "próbować", "starać się"],
      correctAnswer: 2,
    },
    {
      id: 28,
      question: "How do you say 'ask' in Polish?",
      options: ["pytać", "żądać", "prosić", "zapraszać"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 29,
      question: "How do you say 'need' in Polish?",
      options: ["musieć", "potrzebować", "wymagać", "żądać"],
      correctAnswer: 1,
    },
    {
      id: 30,
      question: "How do you say 'feel' in Polish?",
      options: ["dotykać", "odczuwać", "czuć", "przeżywać"],
      correctAnswer: 2,
    },
    {
      id: 31,
      question: "How do you say 'become' in Polish?",
      options: ["stać się", "zostawać", "przemieniać się", "przeobrażać się"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 32,
      question: "How do you say 'leave' in Polish?",
      options: ["porzucać", "odchodzić", "zostawić", "wychodzić"],
      correctAnswer: 2,
    },
    {
      id: 33,
      question: "How do you say 'put' in Polish?",
      options: ["położyć", "kłaść", "umieszczać", "wstawiać"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 34,
      question: "How do you say 'mean' in Polish?",
      options: ["zamierzać", "mieć na myśli", "oznaczać", "chcieć"],
      correctAnswer: 1,
    },
    {
      id: 35,
      question: "How do you say 'keep' in Polish?",
      options: ["trzymać", "utrzymywać", "zachowywać", "przechowywać"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 36,
      question: "How do you say 'let' in Polish?",
      options: ["zezwalać", "pozwalać", "wpuszczać", "dopuszczać"],
      correctAnswer: 1,
    },
    {
      id: 37,
      question: "How do you say 'begin' in Polish?",
      options: ["począć", "rozpoczynać", "zacząć", "startować"],
      correctAnswer: 2,
    },
    {
      id: 38,
      question: "How do you say 'seem' in Polish?",
      options: ["wydawać się", "zdawać się", "sprawiać wrażenie", "wyglądać"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 39,
      question: "How do you say 'help' in Polish?",
      options: ["ratować", "asystować", "pomagać", "wspierać"],
      correctAnswer: 2,
    },
    {
      id: 40,
      question: "How do you say 'talk' in Polish?",
      options: ["rozmawiać", "gadać", "mówić", "dyskutować"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 41,
      question: "How do you say 'turn' in Polish?",
      options: ["skręcać", "obracać", "przekręcać", "odwracać"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 42,
      question: "How do you say 'start' in Polish?",
      options: ["wystartować", "rozpocząć", "począć", "zaczynać"],
      correctAnswer: 3,
    },
    {
      id: 43,
      question: "How do you say 'might' in Polish?",
      options: ["być może", "móc", "chyba", "może"],
      correctAnswer: 1,
    },
    {
      id: 44,
      question: "How do you say 'show' in Polish?",
      options: ["pokazać", "okazywać", "przedstawiać", "ukazywać"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 45,
      question: "How do you say 'hear' in Polish?",
      options: ["słyszeć", "podsłuchiwać", "usłyszeć", "nasłuchiwać"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 46,
      question: "How do you say 'play' in Polish?",
      options: ["grać", "odgrywać", "zabawić się", "bawić się"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 47,
      question: "How do you say 'run' in Polish?",
      options: ["biec", "biegać", "pędzić", "uciekać"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 48,
      question: "How do you say 'move' in Polish?",
      options: ["poruszać się", "przesuwać", "ruszać się", "przemieszczać się"],
      correctAnswer: 2,
    },
    {
      id: 49,
      question: "How do you say 'like' in Polish?",
      options: ["lubić", "podobać się", "upodobać", "przepadać"],
      correctAnswer: 0,
    },
    {
      id: 50,
      question: "How do you say 'live' in Polish?",
      options: ["mieszkać", "żyć", "egzystować", "zamieszkiwać"],
      correctAnswer: 1,
    },
  ],
};
